About

Nationalities: Switzerland, South Africa E-Mail: oliver.m.angelil@gmail.com Date of birth: 23. September 1986 Website: https://oliverangelil.github.io/ English (native), German (B2) LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ Languages:

oliver-angelil/

https://aithub.com/oliverangelil Github:

Zurich

Profile

Data-driven scientist with 10+ years of practical experience in programming and statistics. Strong technical background in Python (scikit-learn, pandas) to gain insights into large volumes of multi-dimensional data through the application of a range of statistical inference and machine learning methods. Experience in a business environment managing stakeholder expectations and delivering timely results.

Work Experience

2021 Data Science Volunteer at Ishango (2-months unpaid leave from Credit Suisse) Kigali

> Volunteered at a Data Science school in East Africa, supervising 14 students working on real world data science projects in collaboration with 7 different

global companies.

2018 - now Senior Data Scientist at Credit Suisse

> Used Pyspark and Palantir software to develop pipelines and models to surface populations of clients that pose risk to the bank. Insights from analyses were

presented to stakeholders across the bank, with the ultimate goal of reducing regulatory risk. After two years started managing and mentoring a small team of

Data Scientists.

2015 - 2018 PhD in Climate Science at UNSW

Sydney

Statistical learning methods were used to improve the prediction skill of means and extremes by weighting climate models in order to best explain a response variable of interest. The weighted subsets were then used to attribute the probabilities of extreme weather events to anthropogenic greenhouse gas emissions. Results were presented at a number of international conferences.

2014 - 2015 Research Scientist at LBNL

Berkeley

Used Extreme Value Theory to better resolve the statistics (e.g. exceedance probabilities, return periods) of extreme weather events. Published work in

Journal of Climate.

Technical Skills

Data Science: Machine Learning; Deep Learning; Data Visualization; NLP

PySpark; git; bash; unix; SQL; automation; unit testing; regression testing Data Engineering:

Python (advanced); MATLAB (intermediate); R (intermediate); bash (intermediate) Languages:

Libraries: pandas; spacy; gensim; HuggingFace; scikit-learn; tensor-flow

Cloud: AWS (Sagemaker, S3, EC2)

Documentation: MS Office Suite; Latex; Jupyter Book; Markdown Servers and Automation: Home-built server running FreeBSD for data backups and website hosting

| Education | | | |
|----------------|--|------------------|--|
| 2015 - 2018 | Ph.D at UNSW. candidate (Climate Change Research Centre) Thesis: Uncertainty around probabilistic event attribution statements for extreme weather events. | Sydney | |
| | Coursera: Machine Learning by Andrew Ng Stanford: Statistical Learning by T. Hastie and R. Tibshirani | Online Online | |
| 2013 - 2015 | M.Sc. at ETHZ in Atmospheric and Climate Science Thesis: Spatial and temporal influences on human attribution to extreme weather risk: a global study Grade: 5.15 out of 6 | Zurich | |
| 2010 | Honors at UCT in Atmospheric Science Grade: 74/100 | Cape Town | |

Awards

| 2015 - 2018 | Australian Research Training Programme Scholarship Covers the full cost of tuition fees during the Ph.D. programme (AUD \$117,360) and provides a living allowance valued at AUD \$77,547 in total. Awarded to 30 students / year. | Sydney |
|----------------|--|--------|
| 2015 - 2018 | CCRC scholarship AUD \$15,000 in total from the Climate Change Research Centre, UNSW | Sydney |

Publications

I have (co)authored 24 papers in distinguished scientific journals. Find the full list here: https://oliverangelil.github.io/publications/

Referees

Daithi Stone

Research Scientist at NIWA Supervisor during my M.Sc. and Ph.D. degrees at ETH, Zurich & UNSW, Sydney respectively.

dastone@runbox.com

Markus Donat

Research Scientist at BSC Supervisor during my Ph.D. degree at UNSW, Sydney markus.donat@bsc.es

Thomas Lanz

Data Science team lead and line manager at Credit Suisse, Zurich thomas.lanz@credit-suisse.com